<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts on my new hugo site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drafts on my new hugo site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:3000/drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Falafel, Steak &amp; Biryani</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/falafel-steak--biryani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:3000/drafts/falafel-steak--biryani/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit slack in updating this blog recently, so in the last three weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve made three different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;falafel-burgers:0830ede8480941d5ad56dd7310bcd51b&#34;&gt;Falafel Burgers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/falafel_burger.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Falafel Burger&#34; /&gt;

I didn&amp;rsquo;t make the falafel for these, so it didn&amp;rsquo;t take very long to make. They taste pretty healthy, and I would recommend cooking some mushrooms as an additional filling.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbcgoodfood.com/recipes/5605/falafel-burgers&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sirloin-steak:0830ede8480941d5ad56dd7310bcd51b&#34;&gt;Sirloin Steak&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/steak.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sirloin Steak&#34; /&gt;

There&amp;rsquo;s not much to say about this. Steak with a garlic marinade, rice &amp;amp; bok choy. Tastes fine, but I personally find steak boring.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Sirloin-Steak-with-Garlic-Butter/Detail.aspx?event8=1&amp;amp;prop24=SR_Thumb&amp;amp;e11=sirloin%20steak&amp;amp;e8=Quick%20Search&amp;amp;event10=1&amp;amp;e7=Recipe&amp;amp;soid=sr_results_p1i4&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lamb-biryani:0830ede8480941d5ad56dd7310bcd51b&#34;&gt;Lamb Biryani&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/biryani.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lamb Biryani&#34; /&gt;

This dish was quick to make, and the result was pretty good. However, I would double the amount of rice &amp;amp; stock, or else the dish is mostly meat.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbcgoodfood.com/recipes/4815/quick-lamb-biryani&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A weird lamb stew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/a-weird-lamb-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:3000/drafts/a-weird-lamb-stew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I tried making Moroccan Lamb, but I ended up making a weird lamb stew. The problem was that I had expensive lamb, and in order not to ruin it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t slow cook it. I ended up just using all the ingredients from a number of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myrecipes.com/recipe/moroccan-lamb-tagine-10000000600610/&#34;&gt;different recipes&lt;/a&gt; and then only cooking it for around 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/lamb_stew.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lamb Stew&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like normal moroccan lamb, I ended up making some couscous to go along with it. And it did end tasting pretty good, but just not like Moroccan Lamb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meat is hard. I&amp;rsquo;m going back to cooking vegetarian next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato Cream Sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/tomato-cream-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:3000/drafts/tomato-cream-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed something quick and easy to make, so I decided to make something similar to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000/pasta-sauce/&#34;&gt;pasta sauce&lt;/a&gt; I had made in the past. I quickly found this recipe for &lt;a href=&#34;http://allrecipes.com/recipe/tomato-cream-sauce-for-pasta/&#34;&gt;tomato cream sauce&lt;/a&gt; and started preparing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/cream-pasta-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ingredients&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the other pasta sauce, you can really put anything you like in it. I ended up using fresh tomatoes as opposed to canned tomatoes, and turned out fine. I also added some bacon, because bacon is delicious. It took about half an hour total to prepare and cook everything, so this recipe is another good and tasty option if you need some food quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/cream-pasta-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Final Product&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato Paella</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/tomato-paella/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:3000/drafts/tomato-paella/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomatoes were pretty cheap this week, so I decided to do something with the many fresh tomatoes we had (that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a salad).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/tomatoes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The many tomatoes&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had a Paella in my life, so I decided to try and make it. I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinchmysalt.com/tomato-paella-with-chorizo/&#34;&gt;this recipe&lt;/a&gt; and did minimal ingredient subsitution. The only thing that changed was the substitution of chorizo for bacon. There&amp;rsquo;s also saffron in this dish, which is the most expensive substance on the planet - I think it just helps adds colour as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really smell or taste like much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/paella-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Frying the ingredients&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole process was relatively simple. Everything just has to be fried up on the stove before adding the tomatoes on top and roasting it in the oven. The final result was fantastic and is probably up there with the best rice dishes out there. It&amp;rsquo;s also a great way to use fresh tomatoes without chopping them all up and making sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/paella-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Frying the ingredients&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Rendang</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/chicken-rendang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:3000/drafts/chicken-rendang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really like chicken, but there was a bunch of chicken that needed to be used so I just made the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000/beef-rendang/&#34;&gt;same as last week&lt;/a&gt;. The recipe didn&amp;rsquo;t really change at all, and while it turned out to be ok, it was certanily better with the beef.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/chicken-rendang.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chicken Rendang&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also managed to mistake the very spicy chili from the market for the very mild chili that grows in the garden. Needless to say, it was a bit on the hot side. While the dish today was still delicious, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend chicken.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Rendang</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/beef-rendang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:3000/drafts/beef-rendang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite Asian dishes is Rendang, so I decided to have a shot at making it this week. I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/beefrendang_78767&#34;&gt;this recipe from the BBC&lt;/a&gt; and made the paste from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/rendang-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Paste&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a lot of ingredient substitution this time around, but I used rump steak rather than stew steak  as it was cheaper. As to not ruin the meat, I only fried the beef in the paste for about ten minutes and then let it sit rather than letting it simmer for two hours. The result was a Rendang that was different to the traditional dishes, but still tender and delicious without the hours of slow cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/rendang-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rendang&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t make a full Nasi lemak to go alongside the Rendang, but served it with coconut rice and salad. Whilst my dish was a little un-traditional, it still turned out well. I consider Rendang to be one of the most delicious foods in the world and if you&amp;rsquo;ve never tried it, it&amp;rsquo;s something you really need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarian Korma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/vegetarian-korma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:3000/drafts/vegetarian-korma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I forgot to post about what I made, but I basically threw a bunch of vegetables into a wok, added a bit of soy sauce and stock and made something that resembled stir fry vegetables. This week I actually decided to bother with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Vegetarian-Korma/Detail.aspx&#34;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt; and following it properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/korma-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ingredients&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t substitute many ingredients this time round - just the heavy cream with coconut cream and the tomato sauce for chopped tomatoes. I recommend ensuring that the carrot and potato is fully cooked before adding the sauce but other than that, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any problems with this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/korma-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Final Product&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Korma is probably my favorite thing I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far. It took me just over an hour to make and my sister didn&amp;rsquo;t disregard it immediately due to its lack of meat. I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything against meat, except that it requires more cleaning up. Like all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far, I highly recommend this dish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta Sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/pasta-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:3000/drafts/pasta-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many recipes are advertised as only taking 15-30 minutes to prepare but they often use obscure ingredients. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbcgoodfood.com/recipes/412625/superveg-pasta&#34;&gt;recipe I was going to make today&lt;/a&gt; wasn&amp;rsquo;t obscure, but I still didn&amp;rsquo;t have most of the ingredients. Instead, I just made my own Pasta Sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/pasta1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ingredients&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty fast and simple to make. I used carrot, garlic, onions and peppers but you can really substitute those ingredients for whatever you want. I just threw them all into a saucepan and then added a can of chopped tomatoes and two cups of chicken stock. I then just used the sauce to top some pasta that I was making at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/pasta2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Final Product&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recipe is fantastic. It works with everything, tastes delicious and only takes 15-30 minutes to make. If you ever need to make something that&amp;rsquo;s fast, delicious and healthy, you should give this a go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato Tacos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/drafts/potato-tacos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:3000/drafts/potato-tacos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my new years resolutions was to make dinner once a week because knowing how to cook will probably be useful one day. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to make something which I&amp;rsquo;ve never made before and document it here, considering I write very rarely. Today I did a quick search and I decided to make &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thekitchn.com/easy-weeknight-dinner-potato-t-104274&#34;&gt;Potato Tacos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/potatotaco_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ingredients, all chopped up&#34; /&gt;

(Please excuse the phone photography)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a number of the ingredients listed so I decided to substitute the peppers, celery, corn, lime and cilantro for courgette, mushrooms, lemon (which I forgot to add to the dish) and basil. &lt;strong&gt;I would also highly recommend doubling the recipe&lt;/strong&gt; as I only managed to make eight under-filled tacos, not the ten that it asked for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/potatotaco_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Frying the vegetables&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was relatively straightforward to make - I just had to fry the potatoes, then the other vegetables separately. Afterwards I just wiped the frying pan I was using and then used it to heat up the tortillas. The recipe asks for  the peppers to be roasted but I felt that it was a bit of a waste to heat up the oven for something that little. Instead, I fried the courgettes which I used as a substitute and it was still delicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://files.mintco.de/site/images/potatotaco_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The final product&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final result was absolutely delicious and I would definitely make it again. I just feel that the recipe doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow for enough and it&amp;rsquo;s a very good idea to double it if you want to make the full ten. The whole process took just under an hour and I would highly recommend trying it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>